Beatrice Fenton Papers
Beatrice Fenton Papers
1926-1965
Fenton, Beatrice, 1887-1983
1 linear ft.
Correspondence, photographs of work, clippings, exhibition catalogs, and other published work.
148976
Biographical History
Beatrice Fenton (1887-1983) was an American sculptor and educator, best known for her whimsical fountains.
Fenton was born in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on July 2, 1887. She studied in Philadelphia at the School of Industrial Art from 1903-1904, and at the Academy of Fine Arts from 1904-1911. Some of her principal works are the Seaward Fountain in Fairmount Park, Philadelphia, the Fairy Fountain in Wister Woods, and a bronze memorial tablet to Charles M. Schmitz.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Beatrice Fenton Papers consists of correspondence, photographs, and published material relating to the American artist.
Correspondence is incoming only. Photographs consist of photographs of the artist's work. Published material consists of magazine articles about Beatrice Fenton and about others, booklets, exhibitions, invitations, news clippings, and a catalog
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author. Photographs are arranged alphabetically by title. Published material is arranged alphabetically by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; Politics, government and public administration; Fenton, Beatrice, 1887-1983.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Artists -- United States.; Garden ornaments and furniture.; Fountains.; Outdoor sculpture.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Women artists -- United States.; Women sculptors -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Invitations.; Photographs.; Artists.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1965.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, A-W (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Ariel sundial (Box 1)
  - Baby Joe (Box 1)
  - Baby Neptune fountain (Box 1)
  - Bacchanale (Box 1)
  - Bald eagle (Box 1)
  - "Barkley Congressional Medal" (Box 1)
  - Bill (Box 1)
  - Boy and starfish fountain (Box 1)
  - Bronze memorial tablet (Box 1)
  - Bust of Felix E. Schelling (Box 1)
  - Bust of Thomas H. Fenton, M.D. "My Father" (Box 1)
  - Caryatid (Box 1)
  - Dunn, John Struthers, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Dancer, statuette of Anne Criss (Box 1)
  - Fairy fountain (Box 1)
  - Fountain figure (Box 1)
  - Fountain in private garden (Box 1)
  - Javelin throw (Box 1)
  - Karen (Box 1)
  - Leopard, in limestone (Box 1)
  - Leopard, in stone (Box 1)
  - Memorial sundial (Box 1)
  - Madonna and child (Box 1)
  - Nereid fountain (Box 1)
  - [The] One Arm Put Up (Box 1)
  - Portrait bust of Marjorie D. Martinet (Box 1)
  - Portrait study (Box 1)
  - Purna (Box 1)
  - Seaward fountain (Box 1)
  - Statuette of dancer (Box 1)
  - Terminal figure for garden (Box 1)
  - Torso (Box 1)
  - Victory (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Articles about others, 1942 (Box 1)
    Hahnemannian Monthly, v. 77 no. 3 (Mar 1942)
  - Booklets with pictures of works, 1935-1960 (Box 1)
    Art Jury 39th Annual Report (1949); Four Quarters, v. 9 no. 2 (Jan 1960); University of Pennsylvania Library Chronicle, v. 6 no. 3 (Oct 1938); Lizette Woodworth Reese 1856-1935: A Tribute (1944)
    Reese item ransferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
  - Catalog, Department of Fine Arts Sesquicentennial International Exposition, Philadelphia, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Exhibitions (Box 1)
    Ten Philadelphia Painters, Art Club of Philadelphia (1927); Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture, Art Club of Philadelphia (1929); Exhibition of Decorative Arts, Brooks Memorial Art Gallery (1935)
    Some items ransferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
  - Invitations, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles about Beatrice Fenton, 1927; 1938,; 1957 (Box 1)
    Art Digest v. 1 no. 15 (Jun 1927); University of Pennsylvania Library Chronicle, v. 6 no. 4 (Dec 1938); Arts in Philadelphia, v. 2 no. 7 (Apr 1940); National Sculpture Review, v. 6 no. 3 (Fall 1957)
  - News clippings about Beatrice Fenton (Box 1)
  - Sculpture by Beatrice Fenton (Box 1)